<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esteban Veliz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Esteban Veliz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>MicrobesIngraham. March of the Microbes: Sighting the Unseen.
Kolter and Chimileski. Life at the Edge of Sight: A Photographic Exploration of the Microbial World.
O’Malley. Philosophy of Microbiology.
 PlantsTrewavas. Plant Behavior &amp;amp; Intelligence. AgricultureDenison. Darwinian Agriculture: How Understanding Evolution Can Improve Agriculture.
Brown. Feed or Feedback: Agriculture, Population Dynamics and the State of the Planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esteban Veliz</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>EducationPhD Candidate in Plant Biology University of California, Davis (UC Davis), Davis, California, 2017 - in progress.
BSc in Molecular, Cell, and Developmental Biology (MCDB) University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, California, March 2017.
 ExperienceResearch Assistant (PI: Venkatesan Sundaresan)Plant Biology Department, UC Davis; 2018 - present 
Investigating the rice (Oryza sativa) root microbiome, how plants assemble their root microbiome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>front</title>
      <link>/front/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/front/</guid>
      <description>I study how agricultural root microbiomes assemble, focusing on processes and mechanisms that can inform the development of appropriate tools for sustainable intensive agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>(Under construction.)
 Microbes Plants Agriculture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Goals and InterestsMy long-term goal is to develop a microbiome-informed agronomy taking into account the evolutionary and ecological complexity of plant-microbiota interactions.
Some of my interests include:
The rhizosphere effect and plant immune interactions with microbiota.
The symbiosis spectrum of the root microbiome: pathogens, commensals, and mutualists.
Microbiome dynamics specific to agricultural systems.PublicationsEdwards, J., Santos-Medellín, C., Nguyen, B., Kilmer, J., Liechty, Z.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>