<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Esteban Veliz</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Esteban Veliz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bookshelf</title>
      <link>/bookshelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookshelf/</guid>
      <description>Felix, qui potuit rerum cognoscere causas.
Virgil, Georgica, lib. 21 MicrobesIngraham. March of the Microbes: Sighting the Unseen.
Kirchman. Processes in Microbial Ecology.
Kolter and Chimileski. Life at the Edge of Sight: A Photographic Exploration of the Microbial World.
O’Malley. Philosophy of Microbiology.
 PlantsKarban. Plant Sensing &amp;amp; Communication.
Trewavas. Plant Behavior &amp;amp; Intelligence.
 AgricultureBrown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Don’t fill this out if you&#39;re human: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Esteban Veliz</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>EducationPhD Candidate in Plant Biology University of California, Davis (UC Davis), Davis, California. In progress.
BSc in Molecular, Cell, and Developmental Biology (MCDB) University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, California. March 2017.
 ExperienceResearch Assistant (PI: Venkatesan Sundaresan)Plant Biology Department, UC Davis; 2018 - present 
Investigating the rice (Oryza sativa) root microbiome, how plants assemble their root microbiome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>front</title>
      <link>/front/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/front/</guid>
      <description>I study how agricultural root microbiomes assemble, focusing on processes and mechanisms that can inform the development of appropriate tools for sustainable intensive agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description> MicrobesLPSN - List of Prokaryotic names with Standing in NomenclatureComprehensive information on the nomenclature of prokaryotesDigital Atlas of Actinomycetes
MicrobeWikiNZ RhizobiaRhizobial taxonomy and some clarifications of some nomenclatureMicrobeTV - This Week in.. (Microbiology, Evolution, Virology…)Excellent podcast suite all about microbes (ASM) PlantsTeaching Tools in Plant BiologyPlant Metabolic Pathway Databases AgricultureOneSoilInteractive map to compare fields and crops in Europe and the USAProMED-mailLatest reporting on infectious diseases in humans, animals, and plants General BiologyBiological Nitrogen Fixation (paywall) Complex SystemsSanta Fe InstituteNew England Complex Systems Institute</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Sit down before fact like a little child, and be prepared to give up every preconceived notion, follow humbly wherever and to whatever abyss Nature leads or you shall learn nothing.
Thomas Henry Huxley
Research Goals and InterestsMy long-term goal is to develop a microbiome-informed agronomy taking into account the evolutionary and ecological complexity of plant-microbiota interactions in agricultural soils.
My interests include:
The rhizosphere effect and plant immune interactions with the microbiota in community assembly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>